Guide to the James Fenimore Cooper Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Oversize and Other Storage, 6.68; (7 boxes) + 20 broadside folders + 4 objects
  - Oversize
    - Spiller, Robert and Philip Blackburn, Descriptive Bibliography of the Writings of James Fenimore Cooper, background material and notes, before 1934 (Box 31, Folder 588-590)
    - Spiller, Robert and Philip Blackburn, Descriptive Bibliography of the Writings of James Fenimore Cooper, background material and notes, before 1934 (Box 32, Folder 591-593)
    - Spiller, Robert and Philip Blackburn, Descriptive Bibliography of the Writings of James Fenimore Cooper, background material and notes, before 1934 (Box 33, Folder 594-596)
    - "Elaborate Review," Proceedings of the Naval Court Martial in the Case of Alexander Mackenzie, 1843-1844 (Box 34, Folder 597)
    - Document appointing Cooper paymaster of the fourth Division of Infantry, 1818 (Box 34, Folder 598)
    - Document appointing Cooper Quarter Master of the fourth Division of Infantry, 1819 (Box 34, Folder 599)
    - Visas, travel documents, and other documents relating to Cooper's work as Consul, 1826-1833 (Box 34, Folder 600)
    - Certificates of membership in various associations, 1817-1831, undated (Box 34, Folder 601)
    - Documents relating to Marmaduke Cooper, 1861-1864 (Box 34, Folder 602)
    - Maps of Europe, 1829-1830 (Box 34, Folder 603)
    - Gleason's Pictorial Drawing-Room Companion, 1851 (Box 34, Folder 604)
    - Harper's Weekly, 1871, 1874 (Box 34, Folder 605)
    - The Illustrated London News, 1853, 1880 (Box 34, Folder 606)
    - Morning Signal, 1840 (Box 34, Folder 607)
    - The New York Mirror, 1828-1841 (Box 34, Folder 608)
    - Northampton Review, 1851 (Box 34, Folder 609)
    - The Radiator, 1848 (Box 34, Folder 610)
    - Letter patent appointing Cooper Consul of Lyons (France), 1826 May 10 (Box 35, Folder 611)
    - Home as Found, "Webb's Indictments," Courier and Enquirer, printed version, 1840 September 18 (Box 35, Folder 612)
    - American Advocate, 1850 (Box 35, Folder 613)
    - The Attica Democrat, 1839 (Box 35, Folder 614)
    - Ballston Spa Gazette, 1842 (Box 35, Folder 615)
    - Binghamton Phoenix, 1817 (Box 35, Folder 616)
    - Chenango Telegraph, 1837 (Box 35, Folder 617)
    - Daily Plebeian, 1843 (Box 35, Folder 618)
    - The Evening Signal, 1840 (Box 35, Folder 619)
    - Fort Plain Journal, 1839 (Box 35, Folder 620)
    - Madison County Eagle, 1841 (Box 35, Folder 621)
    - New England Galaxy, 1826 (Box 35, Folder 622)
    - New Era, 1839 (Box 35, Folder 623)
    - The New Yorker, 1839-1840 (Box 35, Folder 624)
    - New-York Daily Tribune, 1841-1843 (Box 35, Folder 625)
    - New York Herald, 1853 (Box 35, Folder 626)
    - The Niagara Courier, 1839 (Box 35, Folder 627)
    - Philadelphia, 1804 (Box 35, Folder 628)
    - Plattsburgh Whig, 1837 (Box 35, Folder 629)
    - Public Ledger, 1840 (Box 35, Folder 630)
    - Wayne County Whig, 1841 (Box 35, Folder 631)
    - Various clippings about Cooper, 1928-1972, undated (Box 35, Folder 632)
    - Portraits of Cooper, circa 1827, 1847 (Box 36, Folder 633)
    - Portraits of Cooper, 1831 (Box 36, Folder 634)
    - Portraits of Cooper, circa 1833, undated (Box 36, Folder 635)
    - Portraits of Cooper, circa 1844, undated (Box 36, Folder 636)
    - Portraits of Cooper, 1850, undated (Box 36, Folder 637)
    - Portraits of Cooper, 1850, undated (Box 36, Folder 638)
  - Broadsides
    - Albany Journal, 1841-1842 (Box BSD, folder 639)
    - Alexander's Messenger, 1839 (Box BSD, folder 639a)
    - Boston Journal, 1842 (Box BSD, folder 640)
    - Commercial Chronicle and Daily Marylander, 1839 (Box BSD, folder 641)
    - The Evening Post, 1838-1852 (Box BSD, folder 642)
    - Freeman's Journal, 1837-1846 (Box BSD, folder 643)
    - The Gospel Messenger, 1851-1852 (Box BSD, folder 644)
    - Morning Courier and New-York Enquirer, 1841, 1843 (Box SBSD, folder 645)
    - The National Gazette, 1832-1840 (Box BSD, folder 646)
    - The New World, undated (Box BSD, folder 647)
    - New York American, 1839, 1842 (Box BSD, folder 648)
    - New-York Commercial Advertiser, 1833-1840 (Box BSD, folder 649)
    - The New York Journal of Commerce and Gazette, 1840 (Box BSD, folder 650)
    - New York Sunday Morning News, 1839 (Box BSD, folder 651)
    - The New York Times, 1835, 1839 (Box BSD, folder 652)
    - The Otsego Republican, 1853 (Box BSD, folder 653)
    - Pennsylvania Inquirier and Daily Courier, 1839 (Box BSD, folder 654)
    - Portland Advertiser and Plainfield Union, 1839 (Box BSD, folder 655)
    - The Recorder, 1879 (Box BSD, folder 656)
    - Utica Daily Gazette and Weekly Ledger, 1848, 1840 (Box BSD, folder 657)
  - Art
    - Travel desk owned and used by Cooper, undated (Box ART, Folder 658)
    - Desk set, undated (Box ART, Folder 659)
    - Box made from the ship Endeavor, undated (Box ART, Folder 660)
    - Chess sets, undated (Box ART, Folder 661)
    - Travel desk owned by General Andrew Jackson (Box ART, Folder 662)